linksoflondon.com 2018-07-29

# Privacy Policy | Links of London

Effective Date: December 02, 2016

Your privacy as an individual and as a customer is important to us and we are committed to protecting it.  This Privacy Policy describes our practices in connection with the information we collect, and provided to us by any individual person or entity who accesses, uses or registers to use our website(s) (“user”, “you” or “your”).  Therefore, please read it carefully to understand how Links (London) Limited, Links of London (International) Limited, LinksofLondon.com Limited, its subsidiary and affiliate corporations, successors, and assigns (collectively referred to herein as " Links of London ", "we" or "our") uses and protects the information provided by any individual person who accesses, uses or registers to use this or any of our other related websites (collectively, our "Websites"), our web-based services, and our HTML-formatted email messages (collectively, including the Websites and the web-based services, our "Services").

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is a part of the Terms and Conditions: [http://www.linksoflondon.com/ca-en/about/terms-and-conditions](http://www.linksoflondon.com/us-en/about/terms-and-conditions). Your using, accessing or registering to use our Services is subject to the Terms Of Conditions and this Privacy Policy, and indicates your agreement and acknowledgement to be bound by them.If you do not agree with our Terms Of Conditions or Privacy Policy, you may choose not to use our Services. Please check the Terms of Conditions and this Privacy Policy periodically for the latest versions. 

[This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected by any third party, including through any third-party application or content (including advertising), that may link to or be accessible from our Services.]

**Whose Information We Collect**

We collect information from anyone who accesses, uses or registers to use our Services.

**The Information We Collect**

Links of London may collect several types of information, including:

a)" **Personal Information** ": This refers to information that may be used to identify,contact or locate you, such as your name, mailing address, telephone number, e-mail address, or other identifiers by which you may be contacted online or offline, billing address, payment information, financial institution information, information about uploads, Internet Protocol (IP) address, and time-stamp data, including meta-data.  Links of London may collect Personal Information when you use the Services including, without limitation, when you set up an account or register to use our Services,fill out surveys, correspond or otherwise communicate with Links of Londonthrough the Internet, or otherwise volunteer information about yourself. 

b)" **Non-Personal Information** ": This refers to information that, by itself, does not identify you or cannot be used to identify you. Non-Personal Information does not directly relate to an individual on its own or in combination with other information we have collected or that has been provided.  If we combine any Non-Personal Information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information as long as it is combined.

How We Collect Personal Information and Non-Personal Information

**We collect Personal Information and Non-Personal Information as follows:**

a) **Registration.  **Prior to your use of one or more of the Services, Links of London may require certain Personal Information and Non-Personal Information to create a Links of London account (“Account”) or to enable features or functionality of the Links of London Services.  Failure to provide all required information required by Links of London may prevent access to any or all the Services, and failure to maintain accurate information may result in suspension or termination of access to any or all the Services.  For example, we collect Personal Information that you provide when utilizing one of our Services, such as when you create an Account, fill in a form on our Services, purchase services or products, receive technical or customer account support, or respond to surveys.

b) **Information Collected Through Technology.**   Links of London may collect Personal and Non-Personal Information about your use of the Services (e.g., your Internet browser, operating system, IP address, connection speed, and the domain name of your Internet service provider).  Such information may be gathered by the following methods:

**i. _Cookies_.  **Cookies (including browser cookies, session cookies, persistent cookies, flash cookies and other local shared objects) are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's or device's hard drive which work by assigning to your computer or device a unique number that has no meaning outside of the Services.  Cookies help make it easier and faster for you to use our Services because it can remember if you've visited one of our Websites, and help us provide you with the information you need about your shopping activity and account details.  For example:

**1. _Session Cookies_ : **These cookie may be used to identify users between page loads.  This allows Links of London to remember certain settings, like which products have been added to your basket.  Session cookies are deleted when you close your browser.  Without session cookies, Links of London would not be able to track which items you placed in your shopping bag or cart.

**2. _Persistent Cookies_ :** Persistent cookies remember your preferences and behavior and help us to personalize your shopping.  So, if the last time you used the Links of London Services, you decided that you wanted to shop the UK site in English and see prices in £s, that's what we'll show you.  Persistent cookies remain on your browser until they expire automatically after a set time period, unless you delete them.

Cookies do not generally contain any Personal Information.  Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually configure your browser to prevent this.  Not accepting cookies may make certain features of the Services unavailable to, or not perform properly for, you.  For more information about cookies and how to disable them, see //www.allaboutcookies.com/.

**ii. _IP Address_.  **Links of London collects IP addresses automatically.  An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer or device whenever you begin services with an Internet service provider.  Each time you access the Services and each time you request one of Links of London’s Websites, the server logs the IP address.

**iii. _Third Party Advertisers and Analytics_.**  Information is collected from users navigating through the Services using technologies collecting browser and device information, details regarding use of the Services, IP addresses and information collected through cookies and other technologies.

**iv. _Third Party Sources_.  **We use third party companies, public databases, joint marketing partners, and social media platforms to collect Personal Information and Non-Personal Information for advertising and marketing purposes.  Third party companies may employ a mixture of both session and persistent cookies.  These cookies allow us to make more informed decisions about what our customers want from us.  For example:

**1)   _Social Media such as Facebook and Twitter_. **These cookies are required to enable you to share your shopping experiences through social media such as Facebook and Twitter, etc.  Please note that if you do choose to share through these social media providers that we don't control the setting of these cookies and we recommend that you check the provider's website for further information.  If you connect to your social media account for our Services, certain Personal Information from the social media account may be shared, which may include Personal Information that is part of your profile or your friends' profiles.  Please note that any such information posted or disclosed on the Services may be available to other users and to the general public.

**Anyone submitting Personal Information relating to other people to Links of London in connection with the Services represents that he or she has the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.**

How We Use Personal Information and Non- Personal Information That We Collect

We may use information that we collect or that is provided to us, including Personal Information, for any of the following purposes:

**a) System Administration. ** Links of London may use Non-Personal Information for the purposes of system administration, assisting in diagnosing problems with Links of London servers, monitoring Links of London 's system performance and traffic and to gather broad demographic information about Links of London customers.

**b) Personalization.  **Links of London may use cookies and IP addresses to track features such as delivering materials specific to your interests and informing you of new, relevant services or certain third party offerings, and to better tailor your experience in using the Services.

**c) Performance of Services. ** If you have registered for an Account, Links of London may use your Personal Information to present and offer our Services and their contents, receive payments from you, to provide customer service, allow you to participate in online product demos, surveys, and online sweepstakes or contests (including to verify participant eligibility and deliver prizes) and use other interactive features on our Services, facilitate social sharing functionality, and communicate with you about these activities.

**d) Notices.  **We may use your Personal Information to send e-mails to you to verify your identity, to notify you if we believe your use of the Services violates any applicable agreement, to advise you of changes to our Services and to notify you of any products or services that may be of interest and that are offered by us, our affiliated companies.

**e) Advertising & Promotion.  **We may use Non-Personal Information to assist in optimizing the delivery of advertisements.  In addition, we may use your Personal Information to send you e-mails periodically listing promotions or events relating to the Services or from our marketing partners or sponsors.  You have the choice to opt-out of receiving such promotional e-mails by clicking on the unsubscribe link in any email or sending an e-mail to customercare@linksoflondon.com.

**f) Contact Information. ** If you contact us by any means, we may keep a record of your contact information and correspondence.  If you report a problem, we may collect this information in a file specific to you.

**g) Research & Analytics. ** We may use your Personal Information to perform research and analyze use of, or interest in, our products, Services, and for our business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring and prevention, developing new products, enhancing, improving or modifying our Services, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our business activities.

**h) Legal.**  As we believe necessary or appropriate: (i) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (ii) to comply with legal process; (iii) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (iv) to carry out our obligations and enforce our terms and conditions applicable to the Services and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes; (v) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (vi) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; (vii) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain; and (viii) to protect against or identify fraudulent transactions.

**How We Might Disclose The Personal Information and Non- Personal Information That We Collect**

**We might disclose Personal Information, pursuant to the terms of this Privacy Policy:**

a) To our subsidiaries and affiliates, Links of London is the party responsible for the management of the jointly-used Personal Information.

b) To contractors, service providers to provide, maintain, and support our Services.

c) To a third party in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of Links of London's assets.

d) To fulfill the purpose for which the Personal Information is provided or for any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the Personal Information or with your consent.

e) As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (i) under applicable U.S. law; (ii) to comply with legal process; (iii) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (iv) to carry out our obligations and enforce our terms and conditions applicable to the Services and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes; (v) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (vi) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, our Customers, you or others; and (vii) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

f)  To your social media connections, including social media account providers, where you connect to your social media account through the Services or connect to the Services through your social media account.  You agree that by establishing this connection, you authorize us to share information with your social media account provider, and you understand that the use of the information we share will be governed by the social media site's privacy policy.  If you do not want your Personal Information shared with your social media account provider, please do not participate in social sharing on the Services. 

In addition, we may disclose aggregated information, which does not identify any individual, and therefore is Non-Personal Information.

**You Have Choices About Our Use And Disclosure Of Your Information**

You can limit your Personal Information and Non-Personal Information that we collect.  In almost all cases, doing so will also limit the effectiveness, user-friendliness and/or availability of the Services you are trying to use.  If you do wish to place limitations, here are some things you can do:

a) You can set your web browser to restrict or to entirely block cookies, to configure cookie notification settings and/or to delete cookies already present on the browser or device. Information on how to do this should be provided in the web browser's help/reference section. 

b); You can choose to opt out from receiving communications from us [(i) by checking the appropriate box on the form where your data is collected, (ii) by unsubscribing at the bottom of emails you receive from us, or (iii) at any other time by sending an email request to  [customercare@linksoflondon.com](mailto:customercare@linksoflondon.com).  We will comply as soon as we reasonably can.  Opting out does not mean that we will not be able to send you important administrative messages.  If we need to get in touch with you for an administrative reason, we will do so.]

We might also keep certain information for recordkeeping purposes, as required by law for a mandated retention period, to complete transactions and because our databases will retain some residual data. 

Children Under the Age of 13

Our Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age.  We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13.  If you are under 13, do not (i) use or provide any information on these Services or on or through any of its features, (ii) register or create an Account to use any of our Services, (iii) make any purchases through our Services, (iv) [use any of the interactive or public comment features of our Services or] provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address or any screen name or user name you may use.  If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under age 13, please contact us using one of the means provided below (see Contact Information).

**How We Use Third Party Analytics And Deliver Advertising To You**

[We may use third party analytics and social media providers to collect information about your use of the Services, deliver advertisements, optimize ad performance, and to determine whether our advertising is effective.] 

We use analytics tools and other third party technologies to collect Personal Information and Non-Personal Information in the form of various usage and user metrics when you use our Services.  These tools and technologies collect and analyze certain types of information, including cookies, IP addresses, device and software identifiers, referring and exit URLs, onsite behavior and usage information, feature use metrics and statistics, usage and purchase history, MAC Address, mobile unique device ID, and other similar information.

The third party analytics companies who collect information on our Services and other online products and/or services may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other websites and/or other online or mobile products and services relating to your activities across their network of websites as well as online and/or mobile products and services.  Many of these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies.

In addition to our use of technologies as described herein, we may permit certain third party companies to help us tailor advertising that we think may be of interest to you based on your use of our Services and to otherwise collect and use data about your use of our Services.

We work with the following third parties:

**a) _DoubleClick_. **‘Spotlight Tags’ are used to measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns for Links of London.  DoubleClick cookie information will not be used in conjunction with any Personal Information from other Google services unless a user has opted-in and provided consent.

**b) _Linkshare_. **Uses cookies to anonymously record that a user has clicked on a Linkshare link that referred the user to the Links of London Services. This information is collected in order to enable us to pay a commission to Linkshare and its affiliates for any sales they may drive on the Links of London Websites.  Linkshare cookies remain active for a period of 30 days.

**c) _Google Analytics_. **Uses cookies to enable Links of London to recognize your browser and collect data based on user activity on the Links of London Websites.  This includes information such as the number of visits to the Links of London Websites, the quantity of orders placed and number of webpages visited.  This data helps us make improvements to the Services in order to provide you with a better service.  These cookies are used to collect analytical information about how the Links of London Websites are used.  All information is collected in an anonymous form.

You may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page.  Google has additional information available about their Remarketing Privacy Guidelines, and Restrictions.  You may learn more at www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. 

You may view a list of other third party service providers who collect information, and/or opt-out of such collection of information about you, by visiting http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ or http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.  Please note that opting out of receiving targeted ads will not prevent you from being served advertisements generally; rather, opting out means that the online ads presented will not be based on your particular interests.

We do not currently respond to Do Not Track signals.]

**Third Party Services**

We are not responsible for the privacy, information, collection, usage and disclosure policies and practices of third parties, including any such party operating a site or service to which the Services link, operating system providers, internet service providers and device manufacturers.

**Cross-Border Transfer**

Any Personal Information gathered by us in your use of this site will be recorded electronically and used in accordance with the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and U.S. Laws.  When information is gathered and stored by Links of London in the USA, it may be transmitted between the US and the UK in order to affect delivery of your goods and provide our full customer service to you, as well as to compile accounting and other records.

**Data Security**

We seek to use organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Information. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that thesecurity of any Account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us using the "Contact Information" section below.

**Retention Period**

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as we believe is necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy. Please take a look at the "Effective Date" section at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised.  Please check this Privacy Policy for the latest version.  Your use of the Services following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.

Contact Information

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at

Customer Care

Attention: Links of London   
25 The West Mall   
Toronto, Ontario M9C 1B8   
Call us at: 1-888-295-4657   
Email us at:  customercare@linksoflondon.com

Please note that email communications are not always secure; so please do not include credit card information or sensitive information in your emails to us.

Copyright © Links of London 2017.  All rights reserved.
